You never forget your first kill.
Terrifier is a horror, thriller film directed by Damien Leone.
A maniacal clown named Art terrorizes three young women on
Halloween night and everyone else who stands in his way.
Art the Clown, played by David Howard Thornton.
Tara Heyes, played by Jenna Kanell.
Victoria Heyes, played by Samantha Scaffidi.
Dawn, played by Catherine Corcoran.
Cat Lady, played by Pooya Mohseni.
Mike the Exterminator, played by Matt McAllister.
Terrifier is a 2016 American independent slasher film written,
edited, co-produced, and directed by Damien Leone.
The film stars Jenna Kanell, Samantha Scaffidi,
Catherine Corcoran, and David Howard Thornton.
The plot centers on partygoer Tara Heyes (Kanell) and her sister Victoria (Scaffidi), who become targets
of the enigmatic serial killer known only as Art the Clown (Thornton) on Halloween night.
Leone had created the character of Art the Clown for his short film The 9th
Circle (2008) and then created another short with Terrifier (2011).
These shorts would generate interest for what became the anthology film
All Hallows' Eve (2013), which contained both segments.
With the film, Leone wrote it specifically as a means of showcasing
the character of Art and his practical effects work.
Leone has since expressed regret for leaving the protagonists underdeveloped.
Leone tried to raise funds for the Terrifier feature film with an
Indiegogo campaign, which fell short of its goal.
However, producer Phil Falcone helped contribute funds to help
make the film in exchange for a producer credit.
Mike Giannelli, who portrayed prior incarnations of Art, retired from acting before
production began, and David Howard Thornton replaced him as Art.
Terrifier premiered at the Telluride Horror Show on October 15, 2016, and received a limited
theatrical release in the United States on March 15, 2018, by Epic Pictures Releasing.
The film received generally mixed reviews from critics, with praise directed towards the special effects and
the portrayals of Kanell, Scaffidi and Thornton, while the writing was subject to criticism.
Despite that, the film became a cult film, and would eventually generate a media franchise, with
Terrifier 2, released on October 6, 2022 and Terrifier 3, released on October 11, 2024.
The film explores themes of halloween, clown, gore, slasher, maniac.
The tone is dark and intense.